so good afternoon evone thanks a lot for
spending your afternoon joining our show
and share your stories to our Global
audience and on behalf of the listeners
around the world we want to say thank
you for spending your time with
us hohan no it's my pleasure and thank
you very much for doing this I was
really looking forward to this day and
is I'm glad that we' been able to to see
you uh VI Microsoft team so one day I
hope that we can see each other in
person we both inim City so it would be
easy for us to meet and greet
okay yeah that would be much better I
suppose and in you know for our audience
it's very honored for them to have a
little introduction about who you are
and the work you are doing at the moment
would you please do that honor
first um so yes I am Ivon Ivon I have
been with uh presedential Vietnam as a
chief operation officer
since uh October last year so slightly
more than one
year it has
been Qui right um given the the industry
gone through a crisis I have to call
that the the confidence crisis and hence
the regul setting and the new la law has
been introduced and
affected um
technically first July this year right
some some other Clauses uh already lay
last year uh with that wide sweat of um
introduction introduction of the new law
my teens especially on the underwriting
side have been impacted
significantly um though I think that's
the right thing to do it's good for
consumers um the industry has a lot of
room to for growth as well as um to help
the
Vietnamese life uh being protected
better uh you know the 10% that's that
of the Vietnamese population has uh live
coverage which is very low right um
unfortunately or fortunately that uh
that's that's that's the sky it I I
think we we should see in that way and I
think that know as as a leader in the
industry we should do our part in in in
in contributing that so that's one of
the reason why after years working
overseas and studying and all that I
still see uh this Market is very
promising exciting and I see the meaning
in my work beautiful so that's who I am
beautiful you have a pH phenomenon
Journey working overseas working in
different industry and being a seasonal
executive and the sky is the limit what
you say so and you only introduce your
journey to us in less than 90 minutes
it's not fair for our audience okay so
this conversation is designed to know
the journey leading to what Ivon is
doing and I would like to invite you to
travel time with me would you like to
travel
time um love too all righty so when I
was little Ivon I loved to become an
astronaut so wearing the the astronaut
Su and jump in different planet seems
very cool but life did not give me any
opportunity to do anything except I was
able to interview one of the men who
really walked on the moon his name was
is General Charlie Duke and he's 9 90
years old already so he's one the moon
on the app Miss 16
and so for you Ivon when you was a
little girl what was your dream about
the future that youon we going to do and
the job you're going to you know bring
value to this
world well you know I was born in thead
more quiet you know place and um but I
had a lot of time to read I read a lot
and so I often think thought of uh you
know and especially those the time look
right all the know um the the tree
Musketeers for instance I have already
usual Choice a book and and that's quite
interesting quite adventurous and I love
to to do those things um so as a girl I
was part of the
scout scout Boy Scout girls uh and I I
exhale it I was number one at everything
M you know uh quoting decoding what have
you I love those
activities um and that that's
why I don't know maybe that where my
leadership started to to
develop all right of course I have five
young sibling at home that's how as well
yes yes yes uh I uh you know I I let
them all the way and so you know that's
practice I was practicing that's
probably 10 years old right so it's it's
not it comes to me quite naturally to
accept the responsibilities and you know
uh be uh be the leader be the role model
for from my younger sister and brothers
and of some time uh but the rebellious
trait in me always show
from time to time um so I want to do
something different I want I see things
different I sort in different which is
tend to get me in trouble a bit at
school though I was always a stop one
but ask question my teacher especially
very uncomfortable oh all right people
think that I challenge their Authority
no I don't challenge them I did not
challenge them that was a big missing
understand for me that my curiosity mind
my Curious mind I wanted to know more
and the the question I asked and this
come with the why and still to this day
when I'm working with my I ask the why
question that people tend to get nervous
about that but no I I ask to understand
right so I see I would like to
understand to help right to do better
it's difficult to understanding and then
I'm still learning how to rephrase my
question that don't we understand that
I'm you know I just oh I'm not
challenging you guys just try to
understand and how we can help right um
so so that that's it but I actually got
the one part so I want to see the world
that's very clear and has never changed
until this day I to see the
world that's also when I Middle School I
get with the end of it I think that was
miget T she became the first year female
prime minister and she has se become
my I don't know nor star you know I mean
she came in with flaws and everything I
watched a documentary movie anything
related to her but that was something I
said yeah that is my role model I want
to do
something and I said I said yeah because
she's capable that's why she got there
right she's from an ordinary family and
and you know to work and connection and
all that whatever she made it herself
there and left the country now some part
I mean on high side some good some bad
but everyone else yes a human being in
the end make some good one hopefully a
good one more than the bad that that
that's good enough as for me and that
that that that how it was
no I I I I was very unfortunate I never
met her of course she passed away um um
I never met her I met any of
the leaders you know in the world um but
but I I see all that
to it's just an inspiration right I I
said yeah the
circumstance uh I Vietnamese called um
to right
to so she she she she yeah maybe she was
fed maybe she was born in that certain
start to become someone of course with
hard work and all that but to this day I
I know that that we we need a bit of
luck to get where we are with you know
with hard work but yes we need that stru
of life to to get there as well um and
and so I did have a
m i my
parents especially my father always way
constantly worry about me number one
going to be I study engineering when I
jate he like please get married
okay you know and then and then uh maybe
three years later or so I decided to do
my master degree and then
he indirectly got a friend uh he tried
to stop me because she already got the
engineering degree so hard to get
married now she want to got a master
degree her chance of getting married
would be much Slimmer you know that's
the only my dad wor I was financially
independent I you know I've done
everything without his support at all I
got a job went a job then I quck a job I
want to
do master degree are you mad are you out
of your mind sort of thing like that I
was like I said Dad I'm still not
married so I have to do something better
with my life and my time so there you go
I will do my master
degree right M and I went
overseas and never look back Trea me
completely wow I said
wow so what is your what was your dad
profession uh my dad was um he was a
mechanic he um yeah he he's a self
thought one I
mean it was in the the war and all that
I I I believe he could be a very good
engineer right mechanical
engineering um he S taught himself uh
when I was kid remember that we have a a
small workshop at home we got around 20y
workers and he
produced agricultur machines uh you know
given that the ambo Vietnam did not
import anything oh we didn't even have a
car the currency to import right so so
it's all Sal made and then later on we
going to fixing car engine so that so
for me studying engineering is not you
know something
like a
very strange uhhuh it's yeah it's yeah I
I can see touch I can you understand it
and and for my parents that a practical
Choice all right now when I study in
high school I remember my math teacher
said to me that n you should study
economics you're not an engineer girl
sort of thing you know is see my
character anyway no wow I just went on
so the engineering yeah you w for a very
long time I have a question about you
know whether we not nature or nurture
would be you you know like creating a
characters for person so I see you know
there's some DNA from your father you in
there but the rebellious part of it the
the Curiosity was there anyone in the
family that you can think of that have
the impact or influence on the C you
know the Curious smile that youon been
having over the
years I think my mom mom yeah my mom is
um she's a she is a
she she was I think she retired
entrepreneur right whole her life she
only work for herself
oh she created business after business
and then and then and then she she told
me that I could be a very successful
business person and I told her I I did
not want her life right yes that's all
he said you know kid my daughter said
exactly the same thing to me so yeah
yeah there you go I got it what I I got
what
ier and and so yeah but it's is the
Curiosity I don't know I
mean it's it's still the
thing I think I I I and I credit a lot
to the teachers that that taught me the
teachers I I got in a year four year
four
um that I turn around oh the first three
years of my education my parents my
mom I was barely made it I barely made
it right she she could not understand
because she said yeah you're small I
don't know that what happened you know
but School require certain way of
thinking you know structure and all that
which I didn't have or didn't have the
guidance or that my elder sister flying
through she was doing very well but I
was
struggling and partly because of my you
know my May if I did not accept
anything good luck with it you know they
didn't never come into my mind you know
I don't accept that thing I don't accept
this but I was just very quiet and I was
I was very afraid of the teacher uh uh
for for those first three years and then
year four I had a a teacher from Hanoi
she came in and she very new to the
school she had no fatis Al we are
equally treated so I I I did better but
year five I have an another teacher and
she saw my ability I would exhale at Ma
oh right didn't know I didn't know I was
good and one day she
said you are going to an next dayon I
said
okay location that okay pack my bag and
go uh came back next day to the class
and my teacher
asked her name is I still remember
her and okay she asked how was it and I
said oh my goodness that was the most
difficult mask I have ever seen in my
life yeah FR I was 10 years old so I
told that she's like okay never mind you
try Okay a week or two later I don't
remember but she came to me say oh
congratulation you have been selected
from to the gifted School in
Max H you should go home and ask your
parents if you like to be transfer there
if if so then we will do the needy right
uh I just did okay I went home and and
you know D normally the only time we met
my parents dinner time so I asked Mom
Dad you know I I got this uh what do you
think they both look at each daughter I
think having no clue why I was talking
about and
said so I went
on and yeah my parents said yeah there's
no paper to sign nothing you know this
this is funny right Looking Back Now
everything got to be thought parent have
to side nothing uh just the not and my
teacher did everything and transfer
me I went to the gifted School wow wow
yeah so ion for as a young girl with the
Curious mind thinking about Adventure in
the
future was there any moment in your life
back then that thinking one day you're
going to really travel the world and
meet a lot of people doing a lot of
amazing
thing no I I was just curious but I was
quite content right I was quite content
within the high school I got likeminded
people GI the student with all a little
bit weirdo all right so but we're happy
absolutely happy with school I love
going to school I really love
it uh I looking forward it even in
before that next day just a person work
up going school right uh even any
activities you know the The Scouting
that happened that during that period I
went to that school for 5
years and enjoyed it right and then
that's there I met other other uh
students and they started to talk about
this thing they talk about moving to
other countries talking about what we're
going to do in the future be doctor you
know
engineer and in my
family n because Dad was mechanic we got
business home mom got the you know she
she running her own business small one
but she always been the owner
so I have no clue right and then my
friend all the next people I look at
teachers right I look at the teachers
and even my my uh my aunts two of them
were teachers that was quite something
already but that was it and but when I
met all my friend like you want to
do was oh notion here wow actually there
are choices right there were choices but
still is the
figure there the family thing talk to
dises in my extent my dad was a DA child
so I had no really a lot of Rel that but
when my mom side we are the best doer in
that whole extended family wow
so know and no books no internet you
know that's these thing we you f figing
out and I think I have the teachers
interest they they really interested in
me I don't know what they see in me
probably my curiosity the Quest for
knowledge was there I was reading I got
my hands on my book anything I would
read I ask I ask that those who love me
they see me they they they just way for
me to ask question I sort don't you they
hate me and say oh this is you know this
is a headache right so so I went through
like that and then I became quite a
popular girl from someone very shy very
shy to become someone very popular in
high school uh middle school and then
high school I'm so used to it I'm not
too shy about
that like even I met my friends now in
the US do who who went to migrate there
we met them 30 years later they always
remind me someone very popular School
top student better cocky sometime so you
know small tow girl you know oh I'm a
top you know someone yeah so so
so but actually I I look like that I
look confident but actually I didn't
know a lot but partly because of that
because of that
ignorance so I just car in my life like
that um walk straight look straight and
know um just one thing at a time that do
do do when people give me some idea to
think I would think I think and think
and figure out how to do
that right a lot of thinking actually
went through this hat um but yeah I
think I I I have been very lucky when
when I go and interact with people uh
they tend to like me a lot who wouldn't
and that who
wouldn't so you
know is that that would help me you know
I I
overcome um and do one thing at a time
and just doing doing doing doing and
when leading me to to this point of time
I I set a certain Target and I drew it
yeah so for instance when I work for
IPC at a couple of years I said I wanted
to work overseas right and that tacy is
possible but we have to work for it so I
I think I the moment I start thinking
about that until I really knew my first
thing with IC was in Soul M was almost 2
years okay and in the background right
of course it's like anything Tri error
some position I got to the
interview you know they not look at my
application right and and so exactly the
same idea and I said after that I said
okay I got my boss who interested in me
and said look you want you wanted to
develop you further want to be become a
talent of hfbc and I got sent everywhere
in the world almost with I've been to
the US to Brazil to Egypt to whatever I
mean I been to 40 different countries in
the world just part of the working thing
but I I think it's it's also the they
can see that I wanted to do it right is
the the the desire to to do something
better wow um and do something right
right sometime it got me
into uh how to
say trouble trouble which trouble
because people see that I I I I
challenge them um I'm not uh detic uh
diplomatic enough and not you know
playing politics no that seemly could
and I was put in position of leadership
very
early uh even with a I was leading a
team of 1 people when I was only
30 six years old I was I when I went to
the the Regional Conference I was the
youngest
one and that whole thing people already
in their 40s they was very Seasons they
been that industry long time you know
you know but I was with all the I was
defitely ambitious I wanted to do more
and and I did not even know that I was
already in a very uh big position I
didn't know I was head of yeah in the
senior trans I was a head of trade
Finance uh business it's a bread and
butter business for CH
p and remember that was uh 17 years
ago now uh here now 25 million
year net profit okay I'm not talking
balance sheet because
obviously from and I grow it from 10
million to 25 million in the span of 18
months wow two and a half times wow yeah
I I I I really do business I have't
business myself my mom I'm really a
business person but at same time it's
the the ambition I know and I was very
ambitious so so that's also get me in
trouble in the way I get
Restless right I got restless I wanted
to move up fast you know uh and then
maybe that where I learn later in life
that uh the pupil part right I I miss it
not all my staff can can keep up with
that and and and they find and become
very bossy and you know that's where
somewhere um and I start to especially
when I have my daughter and then we
since she go into school I have to
educate her I have to do all that alone
I'm a single mom by the way I never
married her father so raising her alone
I require a
different you know different
uh Dimension right I have to use the
word right I have to uh change the way I
approach I I got to do and also I
promise my daughter I when
never overpromise her I will deliver
what I promised and that's something I
realized as a
kid
I not been how say I don't I did not
have enough trust oh when you were I had
a little bit what call trust issue okay
okay people said I have a bit of trust
isue uh and so I know that and and it's
I need to
not to have it happen to my daughter
because I am the closest one to her to
make sure that she believe that when mom
say something she will deliver so that
at least that trust you won't have
issue I have that issue and I I I
actually recognize that I'm I'm still
working at
it to this
day and and so that that's where I I
don't know it's the whole thing is a
complexity the the the the I'm still not
I'm reading book about that because not
everybody can explain right I read book
about uh son of my friend call me a
child
trauma H trauma like uh child trauma or
what a bit of that but more of
a detach okay detach I want a Detachment
time attached time right because the the
the the the um the trauma I went to
being trusting and attached to certain
thing and I didn't get it and I got very
disappointed and if if that repeating
become something it become a scar
mentally
right then you know especially even now
don't talk about mental thing right and
I felt like that and I wanted okay I
know but undo that quite a very a
different level right I know so so yeah
it it is part of it I think it drive me
that drive me that I got to be
independent makes you independent faster
and stronger faster and you
know um and until at some point
um being ATT t it's hard for me it's
tough not for me for
others yeah I'm okay but for for my have
Partners time here there but it's it's
it's tough for them to cope with me they
see they see that why you know want like
that you know you see move faster and
Bre lose right
um I I could have uh a heart I could
have a a love sick and could be
heartbroken for a month I wake up and
that's it it's gone oh I would go to
very the dep of it I really go to it I
could draw my sorrow in whatever and I'm
out I'm out done that's it I'm done I
don't look back wow even
want for a person with the grow up like
you you so it's totally understandable
the girl with curiosity born in the
small City in the LA and as the why
questions and got you know a lot of you
know challenging and the ambitious to to
to see the world that people don't see
to see the sky as a limit and then the
people around normally just see things
for tomorrow or today not going for a
week later so it will be challenging and
those for sure you know we create some
distance from you for the rest at the
park and and that probably the reason
that that ion is like I said earlier you
make it makes you just stronger and and
and more dedicated to make you know a
change for yourself a different path for
yourself and that path is not a lot of
people go in that path with you so I
wish that back then we could be friends
so that I can come and I say okay F
let's go
and yes yeah I I I can see that um now
it's it's is very it it has become
probably more you know I came to know a
lot more of other females you know that
that would choose my path but it's it
come it came couple years later so it
was quite a uh quite a challenging part
but uh um I I think it's it's mainly me
I have have to accept it for myself
right I said this who I am yeah of
course I'm working I see still me as a
working progress right uh we I'm
learning something new every day I can
see floor in my personality I can see
what I can do better and there constant
uh challenging myself you know to push
uh the limit um and and and some of the
work and when people looking at that say
look oh why we move from engineer and to
work in finance yes and then we want to
know
[Music]
that so okay and and so when I I study
in engineering school it wasn't
difficult oh not at all wow yeah
I went out every night with my friend
not just party because there wasn't
something at my time but yeah you go out
and talk my friends I became very social
but because I can want to do stud in the
morning doing homework in the afternoon
my time free doet tree was hot nothing
else to do is boring just black
wild and and I got scholarship by pass
every single
exam uh you I I told people study is
easy get a job with the work at a
network is much more and much more
difficult a challenging part I have to
learn right uh uh but I part of a laser
f one by
then finish degree got a job and get
married and maybe got a couple kids you
know that was my normal rote the right
that I'm looking at it just like any
other ghost and I you could imagine I
was quite popular
so I don't think anyone's having
difficulty
fighting you know marriage proposal I
have a couple
actually by the time finish you I have a
couple of
them but the point
was it's it's you know after the very
first big heartbreak that I got I'm done
with that department
right I went to work and I started to
figure out the be in an
exp ah I see
that that's an interesting line they got
posted everywhere in the world and the
best part is they earn 10 times of what
I was
earning so that's how I F in my very
first job right and I was luy to see how
I I get
there I I and I a couple first one or
two years I I did not get promoted I
said how I mean the the path is so slow
I look at the people in my office no I I
I can't I can't wait this phone and I
can see myself I was thinking I'm
actually a smart out there even smarter
why can't I
right so my friend and I we were figure
it out
like actually we need to have the NBA
okay so that's how it happened all
went to do that and I went to do
business and father worried yeah yeah I
just figure it out just with my friend
are discuss and all that when I
committed I really committed Ivon I want
to bring you to the moment that you and
your friend whoever that friend was sat
together and think about and and thought
about why can't you can that person get
better and came up with the idea of
having an amb yeah okay tell us what
happened at that
moment I mean just anything like you
know uh probably like AES
right yes yes this this is it this is it
right but then then we pl out and then
we have you see came up in an idea
probably yes it's still it's hard but
not the hardest spot the spot is to
pursue it it's require
resilience the the
patient and I
recognize I was one of those people I
would have my go set there it will take
me 10 years to get I'll get that
eventually it even it it will take me 10
years I do that you know what want the
2024 cambrid pick the world the year is
Manifest so manifestation so that young
age you have that ability to manifest
your future planning and that
manifestation build up for you to set
bigger goals bigger goals and the
resilience the muscle strength for you
to pursue that goal because a lot of
people will just have an idea but
execution idea is like something just on
piece of paper all the time so teach our
audience
how could you build that resilience
muscle for you to Bear not only the
school but also throughout the career
you know look at the operations is a
unon Heroes you do a lot of you know
like hard works in the backbone not
getting the the the lights and the
shining and and the red capet light the
front ends and right so teach us your
secret to build that resilient muscle
though it's a good question right
um is the
um and you you know that course that
that road not like this right it's go
like right it's a lot of bum bu right
and and and there one thing even at to
this day all my friends that or my ex
boss who know me who knew me for years
and years and he like how I mean he
talked to me he knew that I would figure
it out and and work on
it but the the thing about when I have
my moment of Doubt right I I have it I
we all have that doubt say oh maybe I
don't have it right but one thing I
learned along the line is to to write
out my thinking right plan
it just just it just like the project
everything is triggered as a project now
I know why I was excel at project
management when I study my master degree
I love that subject and everything in my
life I put okay now I put it a 2 years
plan what I'm going to do now I break it
down so you see the goal is not so
daunting one step at a time one step at
a time you see this I learn
English not multip times sell T I had a
good foundation I got a year uh with
private teer with my parents parents and
all that I know it was a great idea my
parent put in my head but I I went along
with them and I exhale at it without KN
and I was a very good
student right so and I accumulated I
learn I read like I remember he taught
me like said okay Ian you got to
remember all this difficult vocabulary I
said how how can I learn it because the
spelling a completely different from
Vietnamese right he taught me like it
you get a notebook and that one line you
write that words repeatedly until the
end of that
line and I mean like a lot of student
they all are I'm very sure all them
receive exactly the same advice now the
point is who will follow that
instruction I
did I took the notebook and I did partly
to corrupt my handwriting I want to now
my handwriting quite messy so my mom
said why don't you do that as well so at
the same time I CH two things correct my
handwriting and learn the vocabul of
English yeah I did so that's the point
yes you get it but the point is in the
end I said CL and again you can have a
great strategy in the world that your
implementation your execution fail is a
fail
strategy it just
talk to that thing this build up the
learning the study for exam the the
thing I could see myself really forced
me to do it because you know you can
look through the window see oh my God
they're playing you know that thing
people playing and I'm sitting here
studying right get something and
hopefully 2 years later my life will be
better I must have that turn of
to see myself visualize it okay this is
how I would be I don't know maybe that
that's how I go in but I I went like I'm
quite a single minded person on that
side wow youon it's really hard to
resist the temptation of enjoying of you
know instant gratification that's why
kids will you know go out and play on
the on the Playard you know after after
school or so but then you say okay
because of the vision that you see for
yourself for two years so you will stop
that instant glorification stop that
urge of going out but to focus and focus
is very hard these days for so many
people you know like at many many ages
so how could you back then and I believe
that for for that path that you've been
having for now you still are the very
focusing person on the go so what can we
do
to help us to stick with the goal be
focused and not be not be derailed from
it it's a good question I I'm still
trying to teach my daughter on that
right but the point
is but to do what you like do what you
like what you like my daughter love
digital art she can see a whole hours
many hours just drawing in doing the art
Prock no problem but the moment you
learn okay you got to learn history oh
she will five minutes stand up here
doing this that listen to this that so
so that is the hard part because
education system require people St
across you know you got to be good at
everything and I I think I'll do okay
for certain subject but certain subject
I'll Excel because I love that right but
in overall I love
learning that's the thing I'm still call
myself a learner this one of my strength
as a
Lear wow the the acquisition of
knowledge and I I I always to this day I
could I could imagine the time if I was
in attin I was among all these uh you
know uh like you
know yeah Deb about democracy debating
about history deting what happened I
love those conversation I could get into
that I can talk nonstop about that and
and that's
why it's it's it's the thing right I I
just I just don't know it just get me
into that like I love to listen to my
father talking to his friends telling
story about the time they were in as
soldiers w i just sat there listen said
nothing just listen it could be an hour
or two I I just sat there wow you listen
you have a gift of listening that the
gift that is a human nature Instinct for
everybody but not a lot of people be
able to do that be that sponge to obsorb
information just be quiet and hear in
the world so many noises now so it's
it's really rare and uh you mention one
word in this conversation throughout the
conversation repeatedly many times and
that is the word that my wife and I
we've been on the quest to help the
people around us to get better which is
the word thinking okay because I we
believe that our thinking capabilities
this day has
been um diminishing for so many reasons
and as you are the learner for life you
are your Works require you to do a lot
of thinking right so you teach us how
have you been growing your ability to
think over the years
youon yeah I think what I love this and
this is what I discover it's lateral
thinking lateral thinking yeah you
expand your vision like it expand it
right the entertain every possibilities
sometime
here like okay for instance right the
first time I encounter with foreigners
they went to Vietnam work study what
happen you and they say certain thing
they complain certain
things I when I first heard that I got
very strong reaction inwardly I I would
not show it
then I would I was like why you said
something like that why you in this
country that you know housing you and
blah blah blah but but now I'll be able
to hold
that thought right and compare contrast
why they say this and why we see this
because of the the whole thing about the
the upbringing the environment the
thinking the
exposure um and and
also the the ability to complain as well
Asian don't do that very well right we
need to voice out W yeah right and and
um I I remember someone
said this caucasian Europe and you're
very you're very unusual for for
Vietnamese and Asian right cuz I I'm
a
person right I I I polish my words
better but I'm not afraid to confront it
I'm not afraid to boys I raise the
question differ but I will I'll ask I'm
Not Afraid in big Forum I ask I'll ask
question um I remember one of my
colleagues said you never give out right
give
up just find a different way to get what
you want and you never give up yeah I R
give
up for the little girl in the and asking
the teachers the question why and got so
much of the problem you know at young
age for sure that little girl won't stop
what she I won't stop
atone I have a few last questions for
this conversation and this question I
want to bring you back in time again
okay because Steve Jobs say that um
basically the dog we cannot connect the
dog and but we can connect the dogs
backward right so I have to all all the
years and and all the lessons all up and
downs and and all the experience that
put on to your your life and accumulated
it if you got a chance to get back in
time and let's pick a time to be
specific okay I would like to pick the
time that you got into you know the the
the the math test and then then you say
that you the teacher congratulate you
right and then and then and then you
decided to you know to ask your parent
but nobody respond so you you decided to
go to to the gifted school and if you
can have a word with that little Fifth
Fifth Grade Ivon wi and say okay hey
Ivon this is our future is going to be
what would you tell
her
uh I I would uh I would tell her one
thing m is uh to be
even prayer less afraid being less
afraid uh um stop thinking too much
about what other people think because
it's none of my business and something I
can't control I've still did that for a
long time until I finally broke it right
Broke Free of all that uh if you want
something just go after it just go after
it than that you'll get it there's no
one will want to hand it over to you um
um and and and be careful what you wish
for because it always
come
with doesn't come right it always come
with with certain thing you get plus and
minus of everything you get and accept
all that wow beautiful beautiful
accepting the consequence of decisions
right then that's bravery to to do that
because somebody would do would do
something but scar to assess the reality
with
me will come with it
come oh I'm I'm trying to pick my mind
for the last question because I have so
many question I want to ask you
so there a lot of people look up to you
okay and also there's a lot of things
that you look for the people who work
for you in your in your life so if you
want if you willing to invest time and
energy to Mentor or to coach somebody in
and you know that you see the potential
what would be in that
person that is youon think is the most
important character or skills or
anything that that makes you as
a as a
leader we work extra mind to gr that
person
H I
um I never hesitate to to share to
impart my knowledge right
tost um but I think what I look for
people I um I'm happy to Mentor or to
coach is to
at least pick one ideas that I get or
some one suggestions don't one I don't
need everything I said
right and
implemented right and maybe a year or
maybe a month later I don't know depends
on how big the the the advice person
thing and come back into s you this is
what I have learned
oh oh maybe just along the line they
said yeah I want to do this I took your
advice and this is and I I want you to
guide me through if they get stuck
somewhere I like that
proactiveness the the thing is people
think oh you know I want to be your you
Mentor me but said yeah but what are you
going to do about that right talking
like this it's not helping I'm not
helping anyone you can read from the
book you can listen the million thing in
the world but no one can tell you how to
implement it right and do by doing it
and come back to me and reflect you know
we can reflect I'm not hesitate I won't
I I am happy to squeeze out my time five
10 minutes of the day on email Zoom call
whatever but the the the ability to take
that initiative and bounce back idea
learn here and there then then then
definitely I'm very happy to
have wow it was such a wonderful
conversation and uh I really look
forward to have more time with you in
the future to to talk to many other
topic that we can pick your brain to
share because all that inside here it
needs to get out it needs to share it
need to pay forward for the people for
the Young Generation for different
people to to to learn from the
resilience the skill the body of
knowledge body of you know works that
you've been having and um let's let's do
it more in the future shall
we yes please because I have million of
crazy ideas in my mind yeah and I would
love to be the person that pick one and
Implement I would love to do that one
you know pick that one and Implement I
really thank you for you to spend your
time to to sh a beautiful Journey really
really beautiful journey and and today
is Thanksgiving so I I say Happy
Thanksgiving to you and to your family
and yeah thank you yeah and uh I hope
that one day we going to be seeing each
other in person and be able to introduce
you to my family you introduce you to
your family and they have a new friend
in life right that's how beauty of the
of living
so yeah looking forward to it and thank
you very much for for the time thank you
very much bye-bye Bye by bye